# **KYLE W. SINGLETON**

Los Angeles, CA (540) 798-8372 kwsingleton@ucla.edu

#### **SUMMARY**

Biomedical Engineering PhD with focus in medical informatics and disease modeling. Experience leading a team in program design, implementation, and deployment and facilitating communication between engineering, medical, and clinical personnel. Proficient at data cleaning and model creation with R; Past experience with additional statistics packages such as MATLAB and SPSS.

### **EDUCATION**

### **University of California, Los Angeles**

Los Angeles, CA

Doctor of Philosophy, Biomedical Engineering

July 2016

Dissertation: Investigating Predictive Disease Model Transportability through Cohort Simulation and Causal Analysis Advisors: Alex A.T. Bui and William Hsu

University of Virginia Charlottesville, VA

Bachelor of Science, Biomedical Engineering

May 2006

Minor: Computer Science

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

### **Graduate Student Researcher**

2012 - 2016

UCLA Medical Imaging Informatics, Los Angeles, CA

- Supervised graduate student team, reviewing and cleaning 500+ brain cancer cases for predictive modeling.
- Evaluated a novel simulation technique for interpreting the external validity of models between patient cohorts.
- Processed cancer data from public repositories (National Lung Screening Trial, The Cancer Genome Atlas).

#### **National Library of Medicine Fellow**

2008 - 2012

UCLA NLM Medical Imaging Informatics Training Program, Los Angeles, CA

- Programmed and supported a tablet based system used to survey 10,000+ patients in three Los Angeles clinics.
- Completed coursework in medical informatics, statistics, and machine learning.

Post-baccalaureate Fellow 2006 - 2008

National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, MD

Section on Stroke Diagnostics and Therapeutics, NINDS

- Designed new imaging workflow, accelerating availability for stroke research tasks.
- Developed a 100 patient case MRI stroke atlas.

# **Undergraduate Researcher**

2005 - 2006

Computational Systems Biology Lab, Charlottesville VA

• Collaborated with two students to create metabolic network reconstruction of Leishmania major.

## **SKILLS**

Programming Languages: R, Java, C#, ASP.NET, MATLAB, C++ Informatics Tools: R, SPSS, MATLAB, RapidMiner, Weka, GENIE

Medical Data Standards: DICOM, XML, HIPAA

# **SELECTED PUBLICATIONS (2 OF 6)**

Singleton KW, Speier W, Bui AAT, Hsu W. Motivating the additional use of external validity: examining transportability in a model of glioblastoma multiforme. AMIA Annu Symp Proc. 2014;2014:1930–9.

Singleton KW, Bui AAT, Hsu W. Transfer and transport: incorporating causal methods for improving predictive models. J Am Med Inform Assoc 2014;:amiajnl-2014-002968. doi:10.1136/amiajnl-2014-002968